# Qaisar uz Zaman Electrical Engineer

+92-314-6061494 . <a href="mailto:qaisartoor@yahoo.com">qaisartoor@yahoo.com</a>

https://www.linkedin.com/in/engr-qaisar-uz-zaman-25612588/

Address: P987/A street#11 noor pur, Faisalabad.



## **Career Objective**

Dedicated and results-driven Electrical Engineer with a strong foundation in electrical systems and a deep passion for innovation. Seeking an opportunity to leverage my technical expertise, problem-solving skills, and commitment to excellence in contributing to the development and implementation of cutting-edge electrical solutions. Aiming to collaborate with a dynamic team of engineers and professionals to drive advancements in the field of electrical engineering while ensuring safety and sustainability in all projects.

## **Career Summary**

I bring a deep expertise in electrical systems, with a focus on solar photovoltaic applications across industrial, residential, commercial, and utility-scale projects. Fueled by a relentless passion for innovation and boundless enthusiasm, I've consistently improved my skills through rigorous research and practical experience. My ability to diagnose and rectify faults in PV systems instills confidence in managing diverse aspects of Solar PV Projects. Beyond technical proficiency, I prioritize maintaining a humble attitude and actively seek insights from challenges and experienced peers.

## **Area of Expertise**

- Installation, Commissioning, troubleshooting, Planning, Operation & Maintenance of PV Plant
- > Expert in On grid Troubleshooting
- > Research and Development to improve installation and plant protection
- > Ability to reconstruct the PV system in order to increase the system efficiency
- > Project Management & Construction Management
- > Effective communication skills
- > Evaluation of Existing Electric System and distribution equipment
- > Performance modeling, prediction, and financial analysis of PV System

#### **Experience**

Zonergy Corporation Lahore, Pakistan

**Designation:** Operations and Maintenance Manager **Tenure:** Jan 2023 – Present

#### Responsibilities:

- > Oversee the daily operations and maintenance activities of a facility, plant, or equipment.
- Develop and implement maintenance and safety procedures to ensure optimal operational efficiency and compliance with regulations.
- Manage a team of maintenance and operations staff, training, and performance evaluations.
- Develop, implement, and optimize maintenance procedures and safety protocols to ensure the reliable and efficient performance of renewable energy systems.
- Maintain all PV systems installed by the company or under a sale contract.
- > Monitor Solar PV systems and respond to faults and breakdown and rectification.
- ➤ Develop/impose O&M processes and tools according to ISO standards.
- > Evaluate and procure remote monitoring and sending solutions for solar PV systems.
- > Lead and perform PV system commissioning, testing, and troubleshooting.
- Process and analyze field data to evaluate the performance of solar PV systems.
- > Performance modeling, prediction, and financial analysis of PV systems.
- Evaluation of existing electric system and distribution equipment to ensure systems safety.

#### **On-Grid Inverters Experience:**

SMA, ABB, FRONIUS, SUNGROW, HUAWEI, GOODWE, SOLIS, GROWATT, SOFAR, SAJ, HOPEWIND

#### **Hybrid Inverters Experience:**

PANDA ESS, ALPHA ESS, NITROX, INFINI, SOLIS, MEGAREVO

#### **Zonergy Corporation**

Lahore, Pakistan

**Designation:** Deputy Team Lead Projects & Operations

Tenure: May 2021 – Present

#### Responsibilities:

- ➤ **Team Lead: training,** organizing and supervising all site managers and project managers ofLahore Operations Team
- ➤ Management: Managed PV Projects through Microsoft Project Management dealing with ON-

Grid, OFF Grid and Hybrid Solar Systems

For Residential, Commercial, and Industrial Loads.

- ➤ **Coordination**: Coordinated with Industrial, Residential, and Commercial Customers for site survey together necessary information required for designing and Proposal.
- ➤ **Installation**: Responsible for carrying the work at site from initiation to completion According to Design.

- > Troubleshooting: Analyzed PV systems giving faults and solved their required issuessatisfying customer needs.
- > System Estimation: Prepared System energy modeling, system yield estimation, commercialProposal and Payback Report for clients.
- ➤ Layouts: Prepared Single Line Diagram & PV module layout according to systemrequirement.
- **Reporting:** Reported daily routine tasks to senior administration.
- > Time Management: Managed and completed different quality PV Projects in given timeline.
- **Designing:** PV Designs on different Software like PV-Syst, Helioscope and OpenSolar.
- **R&D:** To Improve installation, protection and work on new technology.

## **Commissioned Projects:**

Prism Energy 1200KW

Job: Site Manager

➤ Al Fatah Rice Mill 520KW

Job: Site Manager

> Al Manzoor Cotton Industry 404KW

Job: Site Manager

NLC Wahga Border Terminal 102KW

Job: Site Manager

➤ Mr Majid House 25Kw

Job: Site Manager

Mr Naim Ismail 21KW

Job: Site Manager

Aslam Javed Flour Mill 1MW

Job: Project Coordinator/ Project Lead

> PEECA (Punjab Energy Efficiency Conservation Agency) 2.7MW (Five DHQ Hospital)

Job: Project Coordinator/ Project Lead

DOPP (Directorate of Power Projects) 1.5MW (Multan & Faisalabad Institute of Cardiology)

Job: Project Coordinator/ Project Lead

> DOPP (Directorate of Power Projects) 500KW (9 Commissioners site)

Job: Project Coordinator/ Project Lead

> PMU Projects GHSS 14 Sites, THQ 6 Sites and DAC 10 Sites Total 1050KW

Job: Project Coordinator/ Project Lead

LGS Projects 1100KW (12 Sites)

Job: Project Coordinator/ Project Lead

QASPL Indigenous Package 1,2,3 and 6(150KW Megarevo Inverter & 300KWH Battery Bank)

Job: Project Coordinator/ Project Lead

**Watt Tech Private Limited** 

**Designation:** Project Engineer:

## **Installed Projects:**

## **Industrial On-Grid Projects:**

- > 300kw USA Weaving Jaranwala Road, Faisalabad.
- > 102Kw NLC Wahga Terminal Wahga Border, Lahore.
- > 100kw Sohni Darti Weaving Sargoda Road, Faisalabad.

Faisalabad, Pakistan

Tenure: Jan 2018 - Apr 2021

- ➤ 100kw Farhat Corporation Jhang Road, Faisalabad.
- > 112kw Adil Tahir Textile Gatwala, Faisalabad.
- > 56kw Eden Orchard Muslim town Road, Faisalabad.
- > 56kw Suriya Majeed Hospital MerziPura Road, Faisalabad.
- ➤ 60kw Jamal Textile Jaranwala Road, Faisalabad.
- > 75kw Hamza Textile Multan Road, Lahore.
- > 85KW KA International Sheikhupura Road, Faisalabad.
- > 120kw Tariq Fabrics SidhuPura Road, Faisalabad.
- > 60kw National Febcon unit 1 Jaranwala Road, Faisalabad.
- > 60Kw Adnan Mall Rajana road, Pir Mahal.
- > 25Kw Mr Majid Cavlury Ground, Lahore.
- > 20Kw Mr, Naim Ismail House Gulberg 3, Lahore.
- > 10kw Mr, Yahya Office Green Town, Lahore.

## **Residential Off Grid/Hybrid Projects:**

- ➤ 10kw signature beauty salon people's colony, Faisalabad.
- > 5kw Suriya Majeed Hospital Merzipura, Faisalabad.

Internship

Wapda Engineering Academy, Faisalabad Tenure: Jul 2016- Aug 2016

interne

500kv Grid Station NTDC, Gatti Faisalabad Tenure: May 2015- Jul 2015

Interne.

**Education** 

THE UNIVERSITY OF FAISALABAD Faisalabad, Pakistan

Bachelor in Electrical Engineering (Power)

3.15CGPA (1st Division) 2013-2017

➤ PEC Registration # ELECT/68374

**GOVERNMENT COLLEGE UNIVERSITY FAISALABAD** Faisalabad, Pakistan 2010-2013

(1st Division)

F.Sc (Pre-Engineering)

GOVT CRESCENT MODEL HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL FSD Faisalabad, Pakistan 2008-2010

(1<sup>st</sup> Division) Matriculation (Science Subjects)

**University of Virginia (Darden School of Business)** 

Fundamentals of Project Planning and Management **March 2022** 

**Google (Project Management)** 

Foundations of Project Management January 2023

Additional

> Certifications: SEO & Content Marketing (Erozgaar) & Digital Marketing (Digiskill)